[音樂]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：這種使用函式構造物件的模式。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: This pattern for using functions to construct objects.
我有我的建構函式，我傳入了我的初始化物件，
And I've got my constructor function, I've passed in my initialization object,
我正在呼叫另一個建構函式，它允許我繼承它所做的事情。
I'm calling another constructor, which allows me to inherit what that thing does.
我會在上面新增一些東西，或者這將是我正在構建的物件。
And I'm gonna add stuff to that, or that will be the object that I'm constructing.
我將建立我的成員變數，
I will create my member variables,
這些都是我的方法可以訪問的東西。
which are the things that my methods will have access to.
我要把整個州都放在那裡，
That's where I'm gonna be keeping all of the state,
此物件中的所有資料。
all of the data that's within this object.
我將建立我的成員方法，它們只是這個作用域中的區域性函式，
I will create my member methods, which are just local functions within this scope,
其中的每一個都將關閉我們傳入的初始化值，
and each of these will close over the initialization value that we passed in,
或者不管那是什麼。
or whatever that is.
我推薦一個物件，勝過所有其他成員
I recommend an object, over all of the other members and
而不是所有其他的方法。
over all of the other methods.
這樣我們就不會在這個模式中使用這個了。
So that we don't ever use this in this pattern.
然後，任何需要公開的內容，我都會通過將其分配給
And then anything which needs to be public, I publish it by assigning it
新增到傳出物件，當我完成時，我返回傳出物件。
to the outgoing object and when I'm done, I return the outgoing object.
而且，我想要多少成員就有多少成員，我想要多少方法就有多少方法。
And also, have as many members as I want, as many methods as I want.
我想公開多少就公開多少，然後就完了。
I make as many of them public as I need to, and then I'm done.
這是一種非常簡單的製作物品的方法，非常靈活。
It's a really straightforward way of making objects, it's very flexible.
關於這一點有很多很多的變體，但這是基本模式
There are lots and lots of variations on this, but this is the basic pattern
我推薦使用它來構造JavaScript中的物件。
that I recommend for using, for constructing objects in JavaScript.
現在，明年當所有ES6都可用時，
Now, next year when all of ES6 becomes available, and there's some new syntax in
ES6，可以應用於此，也著眼於使
ES6, which can be applied toward this, and also with an eye on making
我們的系統更加安全，我要把模式修改成這樣。
our systems even more secure, I'm going to revise the pattern to be like this.
這就是明年的模式。
So this is next year's pattern.
我將一如既往地從建構函式物件開始，
I'm gonna start with a constructor object as before,
裡面會有很多好東西，告訴我如何製作物品。
which will contain lots of good stuff, which tells me how to make the object.
然後我將使我的例項成為變數，我在這裡使用了一些新的語法。
Then I'm gonna make my instance variables, and I'm using some new syntax here.
首先，我使用的是let語句。
First off, I'm using the let statement.
在這種情況下，使用let over var沒有優勢，但它使Java
In this case, there's no advantage to using let over var, but it makes the Java
夥計們會更開心，所以我會試著用let，因為我們要遷移到新的語言。
guys happier, so I'm gonna try to use let as we move to the new language.
變數名周圍的花括號，在這裡意味著一些特殊的東西。
And the curly braces around the variable name, means something special here.
所以我要做的是，我要建立一個名為Member的新變數，
So what I'm doing is, I'm creating a new variable called member,
我將使用spec.ember對其進行初始化。
and I'm going to initialize it with spec.member.
所以這是做這類事情的一種速記方式，我可以輸入儘可能多的名字
So it's a shorthand for doing those sorts of things, and I can put as many names in
花括號是我想要的，用逗號分隔，每個花括號
the curly braces as I want, separated by commas, and each of those
名稱將由該物件中名稱相似的屬性初始化。
names will be initialized by a similarly named property from that object.
所以這並不能讓我們做任何我們以前做不到的事情，但是它是一些
So this doesn't let us do anything that we couldn't do before, but it's some
用於從初始化物件中拉出值的方便語法和
convenient syntax for pulling values out of the initialization object and
將它們放入我們的區域性變數中。&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：當您說let(Member)=
putting them into our local variables. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: When you say let (member) =
規範，現在規範成員已初始化？&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：它是
spec, now spec.member is initialized? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's
的初始化值
the initialization value for
成員變數。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：所以
the member variable. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So
該語句的含義與let(Ember)=spec.ember相同
that statement means the same thing as let (member) = spec.member
&gt；&gt；發言人2：成員相等
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Member equals
特定成員。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：那麼，
spec.member. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then,
我要用新的康斯特宣告。
I'm gonna use the new const statement.
以類似的方式，我將轉到另一個建構函式，在那裡我將
In a similar way, I'm going to this other constructor where I'm going to
獲取我將使用的方法，然後我將提取
get methods, which I'm gonna be using, and I'm going to extract
我想要使用的方法，並將它們放到私有變數中。
the methods that I want to use and put them into private variables.
我之所以這麼做，是因為我預計這個物體可能會被凍結，所以
And I'm doing that, because I anticipate that this object could be frozen, and so
我不想像在以前的模型中那樣給它新增東西。
I don't want to be adding stuff to it as I was in the previous model.
因為我不想打破如果有人
Because I don't want to break if someone
我想要繼承的東西把我當成了冰凍的東西。
that I'm trying to inherit from passes me as a frozen object.
這也解決了有時被稱為香蕉問題的問題。
This also solves what's sometimes called the banana problem.
有關於物體系統的投訴，
That there's a complaint about object systems,
在那裡你想繼承一根香蕉。
where you want to inherit a banana.
但你最終也繼承了拿著香蕉的大猩猩
But you end up also inheriting the gorilla that's holding the banana and
大猩猩所在的叢林
the jungle that the gorilla is and
你得到了所有這些東西，而你想要的只是這個小東西。
you get all of this stuff and all you wanted was this little thing.
這使我們能夠做到這一點，我們可以提取我們想要的東西。
So this allows us to do that we can extract things that we want.
因為我們現在正在提取東西，
And because we're extracting things now,
我們想叫多少這樣的人就叫多少。
we can call it as many of these guys as we want.
所以我們可以找到儘可能多的其他建構函式
So we can get to as many of these other constructors and take all of their
然後把它拉到區域性變數中，我們就得到了所有的善。
goodness and pull it out into local variables and we get all that goodness.
然後，再一次，我將制定我的方法，
Then, again I'm going to be making my methods, and
再一次，我的方法將結束所有的東西。
again my methods will close over all of the stuff.
再說一次，我的方法沒有使用這個。
And again, my methods are not using this.
然後，當我完成後，我在這裡釋出公共方法。
Then when I'm done, I publish the public methods here.
不管是我做的還是我繼承的。
The ones that I made or the ones that I inherited.
我在這裡利用了新的物件文字語法。
And I'm taking advantage of new object literal syntax here.
如果你有一個物件文字，你只需要說一個名字和
That if you have an object literal and you just say a name and
你省略了冒號，這是名字的縮寫，叫名字。
you leave out the colon, it's a shorthand for name call a name.
所以這是名為method的方法的縮寫。
So this is short for method called, method.
這是“其他人呼叫另一個人”的縮寫。
And that's short for other call an other.
再說一次，這不是必須的。
Again, not essential.
但它很不錯，它給了我們一個，這開始看起來更像是一份宣言
But it's nice and it gives us a, this starts to look more like a declaration
而不是像程式碼一樣，在那裡我只是得到我想要釋出的東西的列表。
than like code, where I'm just getting the list of things that I want to publish.
最後，我要凍結那個物體
Then finally, I'm going to freeze that object
因為冷凍為我們提供了非常好的安全性和可靠性
because freezing gives us very good security and reliability properties for
物件，我們不能以任何其他方式在這種語言中獲取這些物件。
objects, which we can't get in this language in any other way.
所以當我們看程式設計的演變時。
So when we look at the evolution of programming.
在像C和PASCAL這樣的語言中，我們有結構和記錄。
In languages like C and Pascal, we've got struct and records.
量身定做的結構，讓你有名字，有屬性。
Tailored structures which let you have names, properties.
然後是物件[INAUDIBLE]程式設計，
And then an object [INAUDIBLE] programming,
我們更進一步，我們可以有功能或者
we took it a step further where we could have functions or
與將作用於它們的結構相關的方法。
methods which are related to those structures which will act upon them.
我認為這是非常重要的一步，但是
And I think that was a really important evolutionary step, but
這不應該是最後一步。
it shouldn't have been the last step.
所以我認為JavaScript實際上給了我們一種前進的方式，所以
So I think JavaScript actually gives us a way to go forward from this, so
我現在認為我們有兩種截然不同的物體。
that I'm now thinking that we have two very distinct kinds of objects.
我們的物件只包含資料，只包含資料和
We have objects which just contain data, only data and
物件只包含凍結的函式。
objects contain only functions, which are frozen.
這些物體非常堅固，非常可靠，不能被篡改。
And those objects are very strong, very reliable that cannot be tampered with.
它們提供處理物件的介面，
They provide the interface for dealing with the objects,
其中包含資料。
which are containing the data.
這樣我們就可以建立好的API，它們可以自我防禦。
And that way we can create good API's, which can defend themselves.
它可以保持健壯，面對所有正在發生的混亂
Which can remain robust and in the face of all the confusion that's happening
在我們的系統內部。&gt；&gt；演講者2：那麼你們如何配對呢？
inside of our system. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So how would you pair those
兩件事，資料，又是物件？&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：我要把
two things, the data, object again? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I'm going to put
成員變數中的資料。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：全部
the data in the member variables. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: All
的資料放在成員變數中，並且
of the data goes in the member variables, and
它們可以包含簡單的值，如數字和字串。
those could contain simple values like numbers and strings.
它們可能包含物體。
They could contain objects.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：那麼還有其他的嗎？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So any other
對此有問題嗎？&>&>演講者2：我一個也聽不懂
questions about that? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I don't understand any of
這。道格拉斯·克羅克福德：是的，
this. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah,
今天下午我們再複習一遍。
we'll review it again this afternoon.
所以我現在想做的是。
So what I want to do now.
我們需要休息一下還是
Do we need a break or
我們準備好進入下一個問題了嗎？&gt；&gt；演講者3：我能問一個問題嗎？
are we ready to go on to the next problem? &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Can I just ask a question
[聽不見]。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：謝謝。
[INAUDIBLE]. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Please.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：那麼你是
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So you're
我要用這個模式。
gonna use that pattern.
您將擁有您的函式物件，您將擁有您要饋送的資料物件
You'll have your function object, you'll have your data object that you'll feed
將您的資料輸入到函式物件中，然後將您的資料物件輸入到函式物件中，
your data into and you'll feed your data object into the function object,
對該函式物件執行操作，建立一個新的資料物件，然後對其執行操作。
act on that function object creating a new data object to then act on.
下一步是欺騙函式物件，這些物件都是從不改變的函式
The next in the cheat of function objects that are all functions which never change
是不變的，但是
are immutable but
他們將建立新的資料集。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：對。
they'll create new data sets. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right.
每次我們呼叫這個建構函式，我們都會得到一個新的東西，
Each time we call this constructor, we get a new thing and with it,
它的功能正常執行。
it's functions go.
它將關閉，無論您需要處理什麼物件。
It will close over, whatever objects you need to work on.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：本身和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: In itself and
這是你要建立的資料，這些資料都很漂亮，它會給你
it's data that you were to create, it is all beautiful and it's going to give you
新資訊傳出。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：資料是可變的
new information out of. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The data is mutable
但只能在函式範圍內，不能從外部進行變異，
but only within the function scope, you cannot mutate it from outside,
除了通過盒子。&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：所以
except through the box. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So
凍結並不意味著你可以改變它自己，如果你加起來的話
freeze doesn't mean that you can change its own if you add up
這些功能。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：對。
the functions. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：[相聲]給出新的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [CROSSTALK] to give a new
輸入。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：凍結僅啟用
input. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Freeze is only on
包含函式的物件。
the object containing the functions.
函式本身仍然可以自由地對任何
The functions themselves are still free to act on anything with
一個結案陳詞。&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：好的。
a close. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
來追上你。&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：可以
To just catch up to you. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Could
請回到上一張幻燈片。
you go back to the previous slide, please.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：可能是5和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And it could be five and
可能會吧。道格拉斯·克羅克福德：是的，但是
it could be. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, but
那是&gt；&gt；演講者2：它可以是你的任何東西
that's &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It could be anything you
想要。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：什麼都行
want. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's anything
您希望傳遞給建構函式。
you want to pass to a constructor.
&gt；&gt；演講者2：我想我被
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I think I'm confused by
事實上&gt；&gt；演講者2：什麼
the fact that &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: What
另一個建構函式是否建立了一個尚未建立的
is the other constructor do if creates a not yet
另一個物體。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：對。
another object that. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right.
IF提供了一種繼承其他東西的方式。
If provides a means of inheriting something else.
這就是你在這件事上繼承的方式。
This is how you would do inheritance in this matter.
如果您不需要繼承其他東西，那麼
If you don't need to inherit from something else, then
開始時不要成為空物件。&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：或可以是以下值
just start without being an empty object. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Or could be some values that
道格拉斯·克羅克福德：你可以指定？&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：隨便什麼，
you could assign? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Whatever,
嗯。&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：i
yeah. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I
我不明白這和你有什麼關係，跟工作有什麼關係。
don't understand how this is related to you, to work.
你祝賀我們五分鐘前做了一件事，
You congratulated us for doing something five minutes ago that,
我已經用一個節點這樣做了一年了。
I've been doing that with a node for a year.
這對我來說仍然沒有任何意義，我是說，這對我來說是有意義的。
And this still doesn't make any sense to, I mean, this makes sense to me.
我不明白我們之間的關係，我們之間的關係，
I don't understand the relationship, what we are passing,
我們正在將一個函式傳遞給-&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：關係是，
we are passing a function in- &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The relationship is,
只有當您瞭解如何使用閉包和函式作用域時，這才是可能的。
this is only possible if you understand how to use closure and function scope.
[聲音]這是你現在可以做的事情。&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：好的。
[SOUND] Which is something you can do now. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: All right.